so hi this is Joe brewer just wanted to
give an update to all of my patreon
supporters to let you know a bit about
what we're doing with the Center for
Applied cultural evolution that we just
launched because this is really what you
are supporting um just you know between
us the only funding that this
organization has right now is the
funding you are providing so quite
literally you are making this happen and
so I wanted to give you a couple of
updates as you may know we have a
website we launched it about two weeks
ago
we've already got a few hundred people
following us on Twitter more than three
hundred people following us on Facebook
about 160 people signed up on our
newsletter and so we're starting to
build a modest audience around this but
what I think is really exciting is I'm
having some great conversations with a
group of social entrepreneurs in Mexico
in Brazil and in Chile about creating
what we're calling the cultural
evolution toolkit and this is meant to
be a curriculum of tools and frameworks
for helping people who are trying to be
changemakers to learn how to develop
themselves as empowered agents and
giving them tools and trainings for how
to make themselves more effective as
people trying to create change and also
giving them tools and frameworks for
understanding the system-level
complexities of what happens in the
messiness of human social systems that
there is really powerful tools and the
social science research that reveals
some of these structures these
mechanisms and patterns that aren't into
it over obvious so by having vetted
rigorous research supporting the way
that they you know change the hope is
that they'll become more effective at
the same time I have all started a
conversation with a blog post on medium
that I wrote last week about
universities becoming learning platforms
for bio regional resilience so the basic
idea here is that all over the planet
changes happening so quickly that most
communities are going to be disrupted
and negative
whether it's by environmental issues
like droughts and wildfires and floods
sea level rises if the the communities
are on the coasts of the world's oceans
or if it's more of a social disarray
because of tribalism and fragmentation
political confrontations the loss of
cooperation and Trust or you know the
things that come out of the drivers of
inequality they're there a whole set of
things like this that are going to
affect communities and what what I
really see as being important is for
there to be a meshwork of people and
organizations within communities that
are increasingly connected into feedback
loops of learning with the environments
that they're embedded in but also not
just the environments as in nature but
the environments as in the social
environments what are the worldviews
that people have the values that they
act on the social norms that shape what
is considered acceptable or unacceptable
behavior the structures and institutions
the business practices the ways that
policies are formed the the modes or
methods of cooperation there are so many
different ways that communities might do
things so it's going to be very
important for people who are in
different parts of the world to know how
to manage what's going on in their own
backyards at the same time they need to
be able to work at a large enough scale
and this is why I've picked the scale of
the bioregion to be able to coordinate
their efforts with bioregions in other
parts of the world to try to cheer jeev
global goals so we already know about
carbon dioxide levels that are the focus
of climate policies but there are also
things like stopping deforestation
there's a really disturbing study that
just came out suggesting that if 3
percent more of the Amazon rainforest is
cut down that the ability of the entire
forest ecosystem to fuel its pumping
process of bringing in moisture and
replenishing itself then basically that
engine of thermodynamics and an energy
transfer may collapse and unravel which
would have catastrophic effects globally
so there are similar things happening in
other parts of the world what this means
is that we need to create really
learning environments the argument that
I make in that paper is that
universities happen to be located in
population centers they tend to be
located in cities and so they can work
as partners with increasing depth of
relationship with the cities they're in
bedlam and the larger regions of cities
are part of so this is just two ways
that you know right out of the gate as
we launched this research Center we are
doing things to try to help so we're
creating curriculum materials that will
be shared with change makers around the
world starting in Latin America with
things being written in English but
immediately translated into Spanish in
French or Spanish and Portuguese with
plans to expand and expand that to other
languages later but also starting to
build a conversation around
cross-cutting themes like the future of
universities the relationships to cities
and the bio regions to start to
stimulate discussion about the visionary
things we need to do so they sort of a
few things that we have going on in the
background that you are funding and
making possible and I just want to thank
you for your support and really tell you
that we literally could not do this
without you you are our lifeline so
thank you and make comments below this
video or below the blog post that will
put up on patreon and let's discuss how
you can get involved and we can begin to
do this work together
onward fellow humans